PRAVEEN PUROHIT

Delhi | (+91) 981-063-3204 | email: Purohit@MakeThingsHappen.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/purohit/

A creative, Agile and DevOps leader-coach, and a technical delivery lead with a track record of delivering complex projects with large teams. Led multiple client engagements and accounts. A Data Science and Machine learning enthusiast. Pursuing Masters in Data Science with UIUC (US top 5). Deep experience in building BFSI / Investment banking, Investment management(401k) and HR applications. 25 years IT experience. Strong people, leadership, client management and presentation skills. Agile, Google cloud and MongoDB certified

client management and presentation skills. Aglie, Google cloud and MongoDB certified		
Agile and DevOps Skills Coach and practitioner in Scrum, Kanban, SAFe, DevOps metrics measurement, CI/CD, Automation, BDD, Story boarding, User Story workshops, Value stream identification workshops, Jira, Azure DevOps (ADO). Scrum and SAFe certified	Technology Skills Data Curation, Statistical analysis of Data, R Language, Python, Google Cloud, Machine Learning, PowerBI, MongoDB. Google Cloud certified. MongoDB univ. certified	
Management skills Digital transformation consulting, Team building, New skill development, ODC setup and execution, P&L/ Account management, Sales and Business Development, Team leadership, Design thinking based solutioning, Strong presentation skills. Duarte and Dale Carnegie certified.	Domain Skills Investment banking and Capital markets, Regulatory reporting, Investment management, HR systems	

PROFILE	RESULTING II	ACCOMPLISHMENTS	
7+ years as an Engineering / DevOps and agile transformations		l Agile and Devops Transformation for multiple large pagements – HSBC, UBS, CMRS, ADIA, Phillips 66	
An avid technology learner		ng MCS in Data Science. Learnt R, Python, MongoDB, Google ud. Certified in Google cloud and MongoDB.	
20+ years as Technical Delivery Lead	Spa	Delivered projects on Java, .Net, C++, Python, Hadoop, Scala, Spark, MongoDB and Azure for Fidelity, RBS, UBS, HSBC and Phillips 66 with portfolios of 20 million USD annually	
16+ years' experience in leading global delivery teams ar setting up ODCs		up Fidelity, RBS, UBS, HSBC, Phillips 66 ODCs with 225+ int. Trained teams on big data, cloud, Agile	
14 years delivering projects for BFSI, Investment banking	Ris	ccessfully delivered projects for RBS (cross asset), UBS (ED k), HSBC (cross asset risk), CMRS (EMIR Dodd-Frank regulatory orting)	
7 years delivering projects in Investment management (4		ivered rewrite of 401k.com (backend plus front end) and One- elity initiative	
14+ years in managing Client relationships, sales and bus development		naged relationships for RBS, UBS, HSBC, Phillips 66. Sold and w RBS account to 12M+ USD annually	

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Masters in Computer Science in Data Science.
 University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
 - o Data Curation
 - o Statistical analysis of Data using R
- Google Cloud Certified Professional Data Engineer
- Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM)
- Certified Scrum Professional (CSP)
- Certified SAFe Agelist
- MongoDB University certified Developer
- Bachelor in Technology in Computer Engineering. 1991-95

2020-Present

GPA 4.0/4.0 Completion August 2020

EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY

PUBLICIS SAPIENT, GURGAON, INDIA	SENIOR DIRECTOR	2006 — 2020		
- Agile and DevOps Coach for Phillips 66		2019 — 2020		
- Transformation Consultant for MENA.		2018 — 2019		
- BigData & Agile delivery lead for HSBC risk externalization program		2016 — 2018		
- Technical Delivery lead for UBS ODC and Agile coach		2014 — 2016		
- Product development lead		2013 — 2014		
- Global Capacity Planning Lead		2012 — 2013		
- RBS ODC Technical Delivery Lead		2006 — 2011		
Key Responsibilities				
- Agile and DevOps coach				
- Waterfall to Agile and DevOps transformation	2 Die Data avaigete			
- Technical Delivery lead of Java, .Net, Python, Azure, GCP, Big Data projects				
ODC setup and rampup Skill building: incremental and burst				
- Team building and setup				
- Capacity management				
- Client Executive				
- Sales and Business Development				
Sales and Bosiness Sevelopment				
FIDELITY INVESTMENTS, MA, USA	SENIOR DEVELOPMENT MANAGER	2000 — 2006		
- ODC Technical Delivery Lead for FeB-I BU, Bangalore		2004 — 2006		
- Senior Development Manager		2002 — 2003		
- Development Manager		2001 — 2002		
- Architect and Lead developer		2000 — 2001		
Key Responsibilities				
- Expat assignment to setup Fidelity eBuisness in Bangalore				
- Team building and setup to deliver projects from offshore	Team building and setup to deliver projects from offshore for 401k.com			
- Program management portfolio of complex cross organization projects				
- Project management				
- Architect				
- Developer using VC++ 6, VB 6, COM/DCOM, MTS, MSMQ, IIS, XML, ASP, HTML, DHTML, MS SQL				
INFINIUM SOFTWARE, MA, USA	SENIOR SOFTWARE CONSULTANT	1997 — 2000		
INTINIOM SOFT WARE, MA, OSA	SENIOR SOLLWARE CONSOLITANT	1997 — 2000		
Key Responsibilities - Architect				
- Development in COM, DCOM, MTS, IIS, MSMQ, VC++, VB, ASP, XML, DHTML, MSSQL, and related technologies.				
NIIT SOFTWARE EXPORTS, DELHI, INDIA	SOFTWARE ENGINEER	1995 — 1997		
Key Responsibilities				

- Development in Visual C++, Visual Basic, ASP, DHTML, SQL Server